welcome to the eighth episode of under
the hood so when we started this series
the very first episode was about AI
where back then we talked about a little
bit about prompt engineering and um and
and kind of scratched the surface and
what what this llm was about uh and then
we thought that was about time to do a
another another episode on AI and and
we'll look into some slightly different
topics this time so with me today I have
Claus hi Claus hello um class you've
been working with um data science and
and AI for for quite some years now so
please you know tell us a little bit
introduce yourself and tell us a little
bit about yourself sure yeah so my name
is Claus marus Hansen I work um as a
principal engineer on business Central
uh all things AI so I actually I was
thinking about it um and looking back I
started working on AI and machine
learning in 2005 so it's 20 years ago so
before LM was thing yeah before llm was
a thing so so we were we were building
sensors for cars to record uh road
conditions and then we used machine
learning models to uh detect whether the
road was IC or not and then warn warn
the driver predictions so so that was
the uh traditional that was the
tradition traditional machine Lear
machine learning and and that's also
what I did uh when I joined business
Central back in the day so nav so I was
part of building the first machine
learning and AI features so the
forecasting uh feature in business
Central um classification the regression
and the image analysis things so the the
early AI it's fair to say you were the
one who introduced AI in business
Central yeah guilty yeah all right all
right so you also worked on other
products um other than which you're not
business Central yes uh so after
business Central I've worked on uh on
powerbi uh for a longer period so this
was back in the days before there was
any AI in in powerbi so um some of the
things we did was to uh do Automated
machine learning so this idea that you
come with you come with your business
data um you want to predict something in
your business data but you don't have
necessarily have the skills or you don't
have a data scientist to massage your
data and do so we did automated that for
for people um we also built some of the
um well we built the first AI visuals as
they're called in powerbi so if you ever
use powerbi and use uh key influencers
decomposition tree analysis sorry
anomaly detection things like that
that's something I built the at least
the back end of so the idea is that you
you know you put all your data on a
report and then you can add these
visuals for example key influencers you
can you can tell okay what is the thing
that most influences your sale in
Germany or something like that so we do
run these machine learning models in the
background um or find an anomal in the
list of find anom in your sales or in
your I don't whatever you can do in
powerbi um and these features are still
available in powerbi yes they are still
available and widely used and okay and
then interestingly one of the last ones
I built was um or we built was called
smart narrative so this idea of you put
a lot of stuff on your powerbi dashboard
and now you want a textual explanation
of what's there right so a summary uh
and that's uh that sounds very much like
large language model and generative AI
but this was before generative AI so
that was not using there was no gbt
there was right around the time of gbt 3
so we had to build all this kind of by
hand okay and that's one of the things
that are much easier today with the LMS
all right yeah Okay cool so um so we are
going to talk
today we're going to talk a little bit
about small language models because
everybody is a lot of people are
familiar with large language models uh
you know things like Chad GPT are built
on large language model Microsoft
co-pilot is built on large language
models but there's also this thing
called small language model so class
what's the difference between large
language models and small language
models right yeah so so uh so it's in
the size of of the models so that's
that's the that's the thing and the size
is measured in terms of parameters so
parameters would be often most most
parameters are weights of matrices that
are used when these uh models predict
right you give give some text it's trans
transformed into some uh numbers and
those numbers are run through a bunch of
matrices and out you get some other
numbers that are transformed into text
and then these matrices have weights um
and so if we go back to gpt3 um this is
4 years ago that that had 175 billion
parameters and so open AI doesn't
disclose the number of parameters on on
the current current models but dpt4 was
probably all of magnitude bigger right
10 times bigger 20 there's some
estimates about yeah yeah and and the
thing is so so uh so the even these 175
billion parameters that's a that's a
pretty large number it requires a lot of
memory and processing power to large
language more large comes in the picture
so it requires multiple gpus to run a
model like that efficiently how many
gpus would you run is required for
running say GPT
4 yeah so so um I'm not sure if they
disclose those numbers but I think it's
it's probably around 8 DVS you need to
run dpt4 um efficiently and each dpus
has like I don't know 100 hundreds of
CPUs or or or processors on it yeah yeah
and and and the GPU is very expensive
right so we're talking thousands of
dollars per month to to to have a dpu
essentially so that's that's expensive
right so then um I mean almost um yeah
so what what can you do to get a smaller
model that that's also performs right
and and and what the the way that that
these models have typically been scaled
is you know you add train on more data
you had more parameters and so on so one
technique you could do was just okay
have St at fewer parameters maybe use
the same amount of data and so on but
and that that that gives some smaller
models that don't really perform as well
as as say dpt3 and dt35 and so on so uh
some of the things that have happened
recently and Microsoft is kind of at the
Forefront of that is you try to to to
make models better by training on better
data so uh large language models are
typically train we don't really know but
they're typically train all information
on on the internet very large very large
number yeah good and bad right so so the
Insight that that Microsoft researchers
had was that you could train on say
textbooks um very high quality data and
by doing that uh you could uh use much
or you could create models that had many
much fewer parameters but were
equally or were as good as as models
that were 10 times as big smaller model
in terms of uh how many how many gpus
they need to run on so probably cheaper
as well yes so they're cheaper right so
Microsoft for example introduced this or
have we have done this series of five
Phi models the first one was released a
year and a half ago with 1 point
something billion parameters and the
most recent five4 was released um this
December with I think 14 billion
parameters and that uh outperforms it
clearly outperforms something like gpt3
and is on par with gbt 4 many so for
simple tasks like summarizing or asking
simple questions maybe it's not as good
as as reasoning as for example 401 is
yeah so but for many simple task it's
probably good enough right and things
that uh things that have math in it it's
specifically trained on programming
program generation things like that it
doesn't have a lot of knowledge about
the world okay right so if you ask about
you know uh what's the largest country
in Europe it it might not be able to
answer but gbg4 would have that
knowledge okay okay but but then these
14 billion that that's small enough that
you can run it efficiently on a single
GPU so it means that it's so you can
even run it at home maybe on your you
can you can definitely run at home it
will be slow but you can you can run it
on a a normal graphics card norp whereas
the large model is practically
impossible it is impossible to run it at
home unless it's definitely impossible
unless you have 8 GPU so yeah something
like that yes all right yeah um so so um
so one of the things uh we that we've
been working on uh recently in business
Central uh on small language model is
fine-tuning yeah so uh what is fine
tuning what is this about you know you
might have heard uh people talking about
it um so what what what what's about and
why why do we do fine shoting and what
can be used for and tell us a little bit
about about it yeah so let me uh let me
talk a bit about fine tuning um so
looking at this um slide here or this
picture here um to the to the right or
to the left sorry uh is shown what you
normally do to to train an llm so as I
said you uh you take a whole bunch of
training data books uh websites and so
on here's Wikipedia for example and then
you do what is called pre-training so
you essentially train an LM to be able
to give in some text use another um
bunch of text um and before a model such
as 54 or dt4 is released they they um
open AI or Microsoft train the model to
for example do chat right and that's not
that's not pre-training that's called
supervised fine-tuning okay so what you
do is to to show or to train the model
on a lot of examples of chats right to
give it some chat input and some chat
output some ation some conversations
yeah and then you train the model so
that is you you change the weights such
that it becomes better at producing
producing chats and then you have like
an llm such as GT4 GT4 that's a very but
that's a very heavy process yeah that's
that's a super heavy process um but we
can do the same as open AI does on this
pre-trained LM and we can also do it in
a more efficient way so there are
techniques where you don't have to
adjust all the weights of the llm to um
kind of specialize the llm so what I'm
what I'm showing here is this process of
of fine-tuning so the idea is again you
have you have you come with your own
data so that that could be even data
from business Central mhm ER you show
the model examples of okay given this
input here's what kind of output we we
want uh and then you do find and you get
another llm mhm a gbt
4un mini that is fine tuned and that you
can use as the similar to the other mhm
um llm um and um yeah and what can that
be be used for right so one uh one thing
that it can be used for is to make an
llm better at very A specialized task so
let's say that you wanted to uh classify
invoices you got to business Central to
a specific chart of account that you had
right that's not something that gbg4
knows anything about probably so then
you could give a lot of examples of
invoices and you know postings to a
given chart of account and then fine
tune and you would have a model that
would be very good at that so that
that's one thing like specializing the
llm to do certain tasks that it wasn't
very good at beforehand but but just to
be clear uh so uh if you if you want to
do that it's because you mean maybe the
first step is to try it out before fine
tuning to figure out as you say you know
you would do that only if you find out
that the model is not doing a good job
to start with yeah because that's kind
of a fine tun still requires some skills
it's kind of you know involved process
right yeah absolutely so it's always the
the case that you know first you start
with a prompt then you try prompt
engineering right if you forget about
that you can see the first episode of
this show right we'll put some links in
the description and and and and if
that's not satisfa
then you can go fine tune mhm um so this
specialization is is one um like
scenario you might want to use fine
tuning another one would be cost saving
um so say that you have a feature where
tbg4 works just fine right it's it's
very good it gives you high accuracy
does what you want but it's just too
expensive then you might take a a
smaller model say gbg4 mini MH and give
it kind kind of the output from gbg4 and
try to get the gbg4 mini to behave as
gbg4 on on your scenario so that's also
something that we are doing right now so
is that what called Model distillation
that's called Model distillation so you
take a big model and uh which performs
for your particular application well yes
and you take the output of that and then
you give it to a smaller model and train
the small model to do the same thing and
be good at that as well yeah so you can
do it cheaper and faster exactly so
sometimes talk about a teacher and a
student okay so gbg4 would be the
teacher okay it knows what to to do
right and the gbg me would be the
student all that learns from the from
the teacher yeah okay so how um so how
how how much uh money can can one save
on doing that which you talk about Co
cost saving yes yeah so so there is
uh the difference between in pricing of
dg4 for example in tpg4 mini is is a
factor 10
15 so so potentially there's a large
saving there yeah so fact 10 in your and
if you if you do something like the even
smaller model that there's even more to
to save so actually you could even
without F tuning if you find out that
your feature or your prompt works well
on small language model without fine
tuning maybe it's even a good idea to
try that out definitely yeah so do we
support that in business Central can you
use small language models yes so um so
what you you can use for fine tuning is
um as AI right so there is this uh we
have this product called s AI Foundry
mhm uh in which you um you can fine-
tune openi models so gbt 4 o gbt 4 mini
and so on um and once you fine tuned
those you can uh you can deploy them
also from AI Foundry and then you can
consume them just like any other
model AI model that you do in the AI
toolkit in business Central yes but even
if you don't want to fine tune but just
want to use let's say you want to I
don't know you do some simple summary or
some you know stet forward thing that
works well on on on on small language
models even not fine tune you can also
do that in business Central right yeah
so you can deploy a smaller language
model in a Foundry and I think you can
also yeah use them in in AI toolkit yeah
all right yeah all right so um so let's
let's shift gear a little bit
um and uh talk about testing right so
how do how do you test this because you
know testing is so traditional testing
everybody knows we all know about that
you know you you write some code you
write some test code and and then you
run it and then you know if it pass or
failed uh but but language models uh
small or large are
traditionally uh not not deterministic
so meaning you know with the same prompt
same data you might have variation in in
the in the answers so how how do we so
we we built some test framework uh
you've been part of that effort as well
on business Central can you tell us a
little bit about that what's what what's
the best practice here what what are we
doing to test these features yeah yeah
so absolutely yeah so the the the tricky
part about Ai and yeah machine learning
and so on is this
non-determinism so um so what you
typically do is you define some measure
of goodness accuracy is an example
that you measure um and then you keep
track of that um okay so um for example
for um the sales order agent that we are
releasing now we have a measure of
accuracy that is um you know given an
email to the sales order agent do does
it process the email correctly and
create the right sales quote MH um if it
does that good that that's good if it
doesn't then that's a failure and then
you essentially run a lot of these and
calculate the total number of runs you
did and the uh successes and then you
have an accuracy so so we do that and
then the yeah the the support we have
for that is the AI test uh toolkit so
these are you know uh normal Al tests
that run uh in this AI test toolkit data
driven tests where the input for the
sales order agent say are
emails and we run the agent and then we
check with normal Al uh you know the
proper sales quote is is the proper
expected sales quote uh generated so now
the the tricky part there is then to get
data for this thing uh so where do we
get the all these emails from and so on
you need a large relatively large data
set so for you need hundreds of tests
for a for a feature like that um and
there um we we are doing data Generation
Um so that's another thing that these
llms are very good at is to generate
data so so um concretely what we have
done in for the sales order agent is to
you know create what we call seed data
so examples of emails yeah from
customers examples of items and so on
and use that as input to uh
gbg4 and generates new data so basically
you have an email that we handcrafted
right or and and some some some data and
we ask the we give it to the N MSA
generate some emails that resemble this
one maybe with different combination of
data things like that and I would say so
the best practice is generally to do
this in a this AI development in a data
driven way so now start by
establishing tests datadriven tests and
make sure then that you drive accuracy
to whatever acceptable number to to to a
good number yeah so so we can we can
test so if I understand correctly you so
we can test whether so we get an email
that's basically the input right you get
an email from a from a customer right
asking for a quote for example and then
um then we can check as you say uh with
with Al code that the proper code is
created but in the Sal Auto agent um if
you're not familiar with it it's a
feature which is in preview uh you we
actually generate we have the LM
generating a reply to the customer like
mail right and where we attach the the
actual s code right so how do we verify
that the email is actually you know uh
correct that you know it's not just some
uh you know giberish uh and that it
actually really answer the the the
customer properly yes that that's a good
uh that's a good point so we we have two
types of uh tests and both have to pass
for a like guess a scenario to to work
so one is these Al based assertions
where you check that the sales Cod was
generated correctly and then the other
is uh
checking an email in in the sales order
agent case and and given that it's
natural language the only really only
way to do that is to get an llm to do it
so we also have support in the AI test
to kit for using an llm to to test
features and we use so we use that to
check okay did it write the correct
thing was the yeah tone correct and and
so on and so forth we also use the same
strategy in in other feature so we have
marketing text as an co-pilot feature
the output of that is a marketing text
so if we have to to do automated test on
that we can't we can't do write those in
Al again we have a prompt that we apply
that scores the output with you know
coherence fluency creativity we have a
PR that says something like here's the
email that you generated does it have
the proper tone does it relate to the
quotes things like that so we do these
checks and ask the LM exactly uh and be
like a yes or no answer yeah right so
back a little bit back to I want to get
back a little bit to um to fine tuning
on small language model because now
we're talking about the sales order
agent and uh and recently uh you and I
did a little bit of work around this and
trying to uh to do some cogs
optimization and model distillation um
so can you talk a little bit about that
yes because there was there was several
parts in it there was both some you know
some syic data generation some fine
tuning some test
uh and then I think you also have some
uh results you can share yeah I have
some preliminary results that are that
are promising and I can I can share
those yeah so so so when we talked about
fine-tuning right we we said that you
need training data you need some L data
input output so so the question is where
do you get that for fine-tuning
something like the sales order agent how
do you get good data um and so the the
observation you can you I mean you can
make it is that okay we we have test
cases so we have hundreds of test cases
that run mhm and if these test cases
pass that's actually a good behavior of
the agent so what we do is so we look at
all our test runs uh we look at what the
agent did in the test run did it behave
properly if it did we use that for
fine-tuning and um specifically the
agent does it the agents do multiple
things so for example it checks the
email when it comes in it uh you know
when the agent is running it operates uh
business Central clicking and uh
navigating out fields and and so on and
there's some other things it does but
the bulk of what it does is these
execute task steps as we call them where
it operates business Central so what we
did is to take you know the input to all
of these
steps uh and the output for the cases
where that Su where the test succeeded
so now we have a data set so this
execute task is actually quite crucial
that's the one so as you say there there
some cheing the email some preliminary
things but but this is where actually we
ask the LM so what to do next you where
should I click where where where you
click where which Fields you fill out
and so that's a quite complex task which
uh you know probably couldn't be done by
anything else than an LM if it's not
trained right agre yeah yeah it's the
heart of the agent so so to speak right
um or the brain could say
okay yeah and now so I have some some
some preliminary uh data here from from
our experiment so um what what I'm
showing to the to the left is you know
we have the this data we generated we if
we run GT4 again on that data MH does it
does it say the same thing as the um as
in the test run right so so let's say
you have a step where um the agent
filled in a value mhm so there's some
input um we asked TC what what would you
do now if it says fill in the value with
the same fill in this field with the
same values then it's correct right so
so that's that's what what's shown here
so for example uh um here on the left we
ran through 10 emails and in
approximately 85% of the cases gbgo did
the right thing so that's 84% accuracy
and that's that translates to you know
um some accuracy when you run multiple
steps but in this case okay so then what
we did was to try to do the same thing
on dpt4 Mini and that's really bad it's
really bad at that um now you can see
the difference between you can really
see the difference between how
proficient large language model are
against small language model for certain
relatively complex task exactly yeah so
so in in the example here if we look at
this um scenario to the left uh tt4 mini
achieves around 30% accuracy so that's a
quite a significant drop and so useless
so yeah we couldn't so we couldn't use
it we couldn't replace we could defin
that step with a small language model no
so so then what we did is to you know we
took this uh set data set that we got
from the test and then we fine-tuned
dpt4 me and that's the thing here to the
to the right uh that shows that if we do
that we get more than 90% accuracy on on
these execute task steps which is pretty
good and in this case it's it's better
than
gy4 um and that that's really good yeah
that that's good um that's
but there's a butt right yeah so so
these are preliminary uh results um so I
think in order to fully you know bake
this and and and ship it we we need to
train this dt4 mini on more data than
what we have in our our test so that's
there's this thing called overfeeding
right yeah yeah so so we do we don't we
don't uh test on the same um you know we
don't evalue on the same test cases that
we uh train train you're not supposed to
do that we don't do that here either but
the thing is that that it's kind of it's
the same you know customers and items
and so on that so the data are the same
the data the master data is the same so
there's a risk that because we have
these data so it's you know we have toys
and and and so the toys have certain
names and that's the items we have and
the customers have certain names so
there's a risk that when we have been
training with this data then small the
small language model that get fine tune
is very good at recognizing these names
and these item names meaning that if we
put it out there to different customer
with totally different data somebody
somebody was selling I don't know coffee
machines different customer names it
might not perform as well yeah yeah so
now back to data generation right so in
order to fine tune a model that we could
release we would need to generate more
varied data emails items and then and so
on and train on that but this is this is
promising okay right and I yeah so that
that's the kind of bad bad news but that
the good thing is then um cost of this
right so I I took that scenario that I
just talked about I plotted in it here
um showing that so
gbgo uh achieved around 85 85% accuracy
but it cost um around 22 cents to run
these these 10 emails in this case
whereas if you look at dpc4 mini it's
super cheap like one cent but super that
uh but uh dg4 mini then the fun version
then hits kind of a sweet spot because
it's it's a little bit more expensive
than dg4 mini it's twice the cost for
for running a fine tuned model but it's
it has the same accuracy as dt4 it's 10
about 10 times cheaper than yeah and
it's still um yeah fact 10 cheaper all
right which is great cool so so um what
advice would you give to our partners
and developers around you know small
language mods and fine tuning I is that
something they should look into you know
what can they do how do they get started
with it yeah so as we talked about
initially right the the first thing to
do is always prom prompt engineering you
know few shot prompting Chain of Thought
and and all those things um but I I I
think the tooling is is is quite good in
a Foundry so um if there is a and
especially model distillation is uh is
relatively easy to do so if there is a
feature uh that uses gg4 um that has
high accuracy but is expensive yeah then
that's that's and you have tests of
course then then that's a all or or data
of usage and and can say which are good
uh predictions by GT4 then then
certainly you could find you a GPT for
me and have the the cost savings well
you might you might want to try GPT for
yeah small language before yes yes
prompt engineering on GC on small
language results that's the first step
so that would be also savings to
start with yeah so definitely looking at
gbg4 mini is a is a good good idea or
maybe the five Ms as well yeah 54 and so
on it's also good and yeah then then
there's all also because there are fewer
parameters in the model it's also much
faster mhm so if you have a scenario
where you need speed MH then it's also
Factor 10 or so faster so yeah so from
from you you you send a prompt till you
get the answer yes it's it's it's much
faster all right right but but again is
it fair to say that when you get if you
get into fine tuning you you need to pay
attentions to the data you're using
that's the crucial part right and that's
where the work is the fine tuning itself
is maybe not is maybe well is as you
said there's some good Tools in in AI
but generating the good data set can be
maybe yeah that's that's that's the
challenge yeah I would say for the open
AI models it's very simple to to find
tune good tooling and uh yeah you you
have to you know have good data you have
to make sure that it's representative
that it's accurate you have to make sure
that you uh you know um don't train on
the same data that you test on all those
things that
uh um that you have to avoid to to to
know overfit so that it only works on on
what you train it on
yeah all right thank you class we talk
about we could talk about this four
hours that's you know it's a very
exciting subject this we think it is um
so we hope you enjoy this episode and
thank you for watching thank you